<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learn Circuit Analysis on Tooabstractive</title>
    <link>/learnca/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learn Circuit Analysis on Tooabstractive</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/learnca/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Is Voltage, Current and Resistance In Simple Terms?</title>
      <link>/learnca/what-is-voltage-current-and-resistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learnca/what-is-voltage-current-and-resistance/</guid>
      <description>Content SummaryCircuits are fascinating and can be found in our smartphones,computer, even the PS5 gaming pad and much more.A circuit or electric circuit is a close loop that allows the flowof electricity.The interconnections of circuit components without forming aclosed loop is called electrical network.Voltage is the pressure or force applied to push current through abranch in a circuit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electronics Circuit Components And Their Functions Explained</title>
      <link>/learnca/electronics-circuit-components-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learnca/electronics-circuit-components-explained/</guid>
      <description>Content SummaryA battery is considered as one of the source of voltage.Resistor is a component that offers resistance to the flow ofcurrent in a circuit.Capacitor which in simple term is a passive device orcomponentthatstores charges or energy for a short period of time.An inductor works same way as the capacitor becausethey store charge but one of their difference is that it useswounded conductors rather than capacitor that uses plates separatedby air gap or dielectrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Ohms Law In Simple Terms? And Why Is It Useful</title>
      <link>/learnca/what-is-ohms-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learnca/what-is-ohms-law/</guid>
      <description>Content SummaryThe ohms law is the fundamental law that relates voltage, current and resistance by using simple mathematicalexpressions. Ohms law is the law that most other techniques (e.g. kirchoffs law, nodal analysis and mesh analysis) are derived from.what is ohm&#39;s law and why do we need itThe ohms law is the fundamental law that relates voltage, current and resistance by using simple mathematicalexpressions which says V = IR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Series and parallel combination of resistors explained with how to identify them</title>
      <link>/learnca/series-and-parallel-resistor-and-how-to-identify-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learnca/series-and-parallel-resistor-and-how-to-identify-them/</guid>
      <description>Content SummaryResistors in series are connected head to tail.A resistor in series allows the same current to flow throughthem but different voltage will bedropped across them if their resistance value is different.Resistors in parallel are connected head to head and tail totail.A resistor in parallel have same voltage but different current will beflowing through each resistor depending on their resistance value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star - Delta Transformation Explained With Tips On How To Recall The Formulas</title>
      <link>/learnca/delta-and-star-connection-of-resistors-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learnca/delta-and-star-connection-of-resistors-explained/</guid>
      <description>Content SummaryThe star and delta transformation involves converting from star to delta or delta to star and we do this when our resistors are not connected in parallel or series.The delta can be structured in two ways as having a triangleshape or pie shape. The star has awye or T shape.Why and how do we do star to delta or delta to star transformationThe star and delta transformation involves converting from star to delta or delta to star and we dothis when our resistors are not connected in parallel or series.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
